(カカシ)う～ん… まいったな。
Hmm…
What a dilemma…
(シズネ)どうしたんですか？ カカシ様。
What's the matter, Lord Kakashi?
Please, drop the "lord"!
(カカシ)様は やめてって！
いやね… みんなに出した任務
あったじゃない？
Anyway, remember the mission
I assigned everyone?
やっぱり 査定しなきゃ ダメかな？
Do I really have to
assess each thing?
(シズネ)当然です！
Of course!
(トントン)ブーブー。
ブーブー。
Oink oink.
(カカシ)蜂蜜酒なんて いかにも
お祝いっぽくて いいよね。
The honey wine's really great,
it's perfect for
a special occasion.
You can tell Team 8
went all out for this.
(シズネ)さすが 八班の２人は
気合いが入ってますね！
この食事券と
温泉旅行の招待券なんて→
And these gift certificates
for a dinner
and the hot springs vacation
is very thoughtful!
気が利いてるじゃないですか！
I wasn't expecting this
from Choji and Shikamaru.
(カカシ)チョウジもシカマルもなんだかんだで
いいとこ 突いてくるよね。
They outdid themselves.
(シズネ)女子たちは これ…
自分たちの趣味ですよね？
You can really see
the girls' personal tastes
reflected in their choices.
That's just cute…
but take a look at this.
そんなの かわいいもんだよ。
これ！
NARUTO AND HINATA
WEDDING GIFT
MIGHT GUY
ROCK LEE
That's just cute…
but take a look at this.
ん？
ありえないよね…。
It's unbelievable, right?
それと 木ノ葉丸は
まだ 報告書すら出してないよな。
Oh, and Konohamaru hasn't even
turned in a report.
よ… よかったじゃないですか。
I-It turned out well, though.
披露宴当日の当直は
もう 彼らに決まり！
Now they can be the ones on duty
on the day of the reception.
確かに 査定をして
ふるいに かけるなら→
True, if I'm to assess the gifts
and make my selections,
この３人が当直の候補だけど…。
these three should be
the candidates.
本当に それでいいのかね？
But it this really all right?
The Outcome of the Secret Mission
(ヒナタ)カカシ先生。
Kakashi Sensei?
ん… ん!?
あ… おぉ！
Oh?!
Hinata! It's been awhile!
あ… ヒナタ！ 久しぶりだな。
あ… どうしたんだ？
What's up?
久々に
サクラちゃんたちと会うんです。
I'm meeting up with Sakura
and the girls. It's been so long.
独身最後の女子会ってやつだな？
Your last ladies' get-together
as a single woman, huh?
披露宴の準備は進んでるか？
ナルトは元気だろうな？
How are your wedding plans going?
I take it Naruto's doing okay?
えっ？ あぁ はい。
Huh? Oh, yes.
とっても元気です。
He's doing really well!
カカシ先生は どちらへ？
Where are you headed,
Kakashi Sensei?
あ？ ちょっと 昼寝に。
I'm going to take a quick nap.
あ… お邪魔しちゃって
すみませんでした。
Oh… I'm sorry to have bothered you.
では これで 失礼します。
お… おう。
Please excuse me!
Oh…
はぁ…。
(イルカ)う～ん…。
Hmm…
(テウチ)どうしたんだい？ イルカ先生。
ラーメン おいしくなかったかい？
What's the matter, Iruka Sensei?
Was the ramen bad?
いや いや！ ラーメンは
おいしく いただきましたよ。
No, no!
The ramen was delicious!
そうじゃなくって…。
It's not that…
I knew you'd be here, Iruka Sensei!
(木ノ葉丸)やっぱり
ここにいたぞ イルカ先生！
K-Konohamaru!
こ… 木ノ葉丸！
This has gone on too long.
いいかげん お祝いのメッセージ
欲しいんだぞ コレ！
I really need to get
your congratulatory message!
じゃないと 俺のお祝いの品が
提出できないだろ！
Otherwise, I can't turn in
this video as my wedding gift!
I'm so sorry!
悪い 悪い！
なんだ…。
So, is that what
you're agonizing about?
まさか それで悩んでたのか!?
Yes, I can't think of what to say.
えぇ… 思いつかなくて。
いくらなんでも 悩みすぎだぞ。
もう観念して 撮影するぞ コレ！
Well, you're agonizing too much!
Get ready,
I'm gonna record you now!
ちょ… ちょっと待て！
うわっ！
H-Hey, wait!
いいかげんにしろ イルカ先生！
Get it together, Iruka Sensei!
(テウチ)木ノ葉丸の言うとおりだ
イルカ先生。
Konohamaru's right, Iruka Sensei.
祝いの言葉ひとつ
思いつかねえなんて おかしいぜ。
How can anyone not know what to
say in a congratulatory message?
You're Naruto's teacher,
aren't you?!
ナルトの恩師だろうが！
それなんです！
That's the reason why!
(２人)それ？
– That's the reason?
Back when Lord Kazekage
came to Ichiraku…
以前 風影様が 一楽に来たとき…。
((我愛羅 : 俺は
風影としてではなく→
I'm going to honor Naruto
not as the Kazekage,
(ナルトの友人として
祝わせてもらおう))
but as his friend.
それを聞いたら
俺は ナルトのどんな存在として→
When I heard that,
I began to wonder in what role
should I celebrate him?
祝えばいいんだろう
なんて思ってしまって…。
どういうことだ？
What do you mean?
だから 恩師に決まってるぞ コレ。
What else? You're his teacher.
確かに 皆さんが言うように→
Without a doubt, you may all
see me as his "teacher."
俺は ナルトの師と
見られているかもしれない…。
That's right! So, hurry up
and let me record you,
そうだぞ！ だから 撮影しないと
ビデオが締まらないんだぞ!!
or I can't finish it!
Yeah…
(イルカ)あぁ…。
But I kind of feel like
it shouldn't be coming from
でもな 単純に→
一教師と一生徒というわけには
いかない気がするんだ。
the point of view of
a teacher to his pupil.
教師として正しいかは
わからないが→
I don't even know if it's right
to do this as his teacher, or not…
ナルトには
他の生徒とは違う思いもある。
But I feel Naruto's
a little different
than my other students.
それを ただ単純に→
And that's why I can't proceed
as a teacher.
師と教え子の関係で
片づけてよいものか…。
かといって 風影様のように→
And yet, I don't think
you can call us "friends"
友人と呼べるようなことでも
ない気がするしね。
in the way Lord Kakashi described.
とにかく 考えれば考えるほど→
Anyway, the more I think about it,
ナルトへの祝いの言葉が
思いつかないんだよ。
the more unsure I become
about my message for Naruto.
確かに ナルトのやつと イルカ先生が
友人ってのも→
That's for sure…
You and Naruto being friends
doesn't feel quite right.
変な感じがするな。
まぁ それは それとして…。
Anyways, I'm gonna charge you
for that bowl…
その丼は弁償してもらうからな！
(サクラ)それで それで？
もう披露宴の準備は済んだの？
And? And?
Are all the preparations for
the reception finished?
(ヒナタ)うん 大方 終わったかな。
Yes, most of it.
(いの)それにしても 私たちの中で
いちばん最初に結婚するのが→
Anyways,
I'm so surprised the first one
out of our group to get married
are you and Naruto!
ヒナタとナルトとはね！
(テンテン)ナルトは 最近 どうしてるの？
How is Naruto lately?
あいつ ちゃんと
準備 手伝ってくれてる？
Is he helping you at all?
もちろん でも
ナルト君より父のほうが→
Of course!
More than Naruto,
it's my father who keeps telling me
what I should do.
ああしろ こうしろって
大変で…。
やっぱり 噂どおり 花嫁の父って
気が気じゃないみたい。
It's true about the father
of the bride being a pain.
なんだかんだ やっぱり
結婚式って大変なんだ。
I guess planning a wedding
is a huge task.
そりゃそうよ 私たちだって
カカシ先生に ああいう任…。
Of course it is!
Even with us…
Kakashi Sensei gave us that…
あ～！
ちょっ サクラ！
Ah!
Hey, Sakura!
なにすんの… あっ！
What's the big idea—!
((私たちだって カカシ先生に
ああいう任…))
Even with us, Kakashi Sensei
gave us that mission…
《しまった！》
Damn it!
– Oh!
(２人)あ～！ あ あ～！
– Ah! Ah!
カカシ先生が どうかしたの？
What about Kakashi Sensei?
(２人)え… え～と。
– Huh?!
– Er…um…
結婚式に向けて
いろいろ任務を終わらせるの→
He's going through a lot trying to
wrap up all the missions
before the wedding.
That's all.
大変ってこと。
うん そう。
Yeah!
And unlike us, you already
have Naruto, so you're lucky.
その点 私たちと違って
もうヒナタには→
ナルトがいるから
いいよねってこと。
そうそう そう！
まあ そうだね。
That's all.
Yeah, that's right!
Well, I guess so.
(サクラ)で で で 衣装は
やっぱ着物でしょ？
So? So?
Are you going to wear a kimono?
(テンテン)
ヒナタの花嫁姿きれいだろうな！
You're gonna look so pretty
as a bride!
(いの)うんうんうん！
Yeah, yeah!
(キバ)お～い ヒナタ！
(赤丸)ワンワンワン！
Hey, Hinata!
アハハ！
(キバ)久しぶりだな。
Long time no see!
キバ君 シノ君。
Kiba, Shino!
元気か？
うん ２人も元気そう。
Have you been doing all right?
Yeah! You two seem great as well!
(シノ)もうすぐ お前を
祝えるのだから当然だろう。
Of course, since we'll soon be
celebrating your wedding soon.
なぜなら 俺たちは…。
ナルトのやつは元気か？
It's because…
How's Naruto doing?!
We rarely see him these days.
最近 全然見ないからな。
まあ 結婚式の準備が
大変なのはわかってるけどよ。
I guess he's busy getting ready
for the big day.
うん ナルト君
任務も忙しいのに→
Yes.
Naruto's busy with his missions,
披露宴のことも ちゃんと
やってくれて頼もしいよ。
but he's been helping a lot
with the reception.
He's really dependable.
そっか 俺たちも
でっかい任務を終わらせて→
Oh, yeah?
Well, we're completing
a huge mission
絶対 お前に喜んでもらえ…。
and we're gonna make you happy…
キバ！
あ？
Kiba!
Huh?
ああ！
Oh!
え？ 私が何？
Make me what?
とにかくだ…。
Anyways…
ようするに ナルトとヒナタなら→
What he means is you and Naruto
will definitely make a happy home!
最高に明るく楽しい家庭が
作れるってことだ。
披露宴
楽しみにしてるからな。
We're looking forward
to the reception!
うん ありがとう。
Oh, thank you.
MISSION REPORTS
(トントン)ブ-ブイ ブイ。
うん？
ああ 綱手様！
Lady Tsunade!
(綱手)ああ 久しぶりだな シズネ。
元気だったか？
It's been a while, Shizune!
How have you been?
おかげさまで。
Great, thank you!
綱手様は 最近
勝負ごとのほうは？
How has your wagering
been going lately?
ナルトとヒナタの祝言があるから
ムダな出費はできん。
There's Naruto and Hinata's
upcoming wedding,
so I'm not spending excessively.
それは賢明なご判断です。
That is a wise decision.
ところで なんだ？
相談とは。
Anyway, what did you
want to discuss?
はい 実は カカシ様の件で。
Yes…
Actually, it's about Lord Kakashi…
カカシ？ いや
六代目がどうかしたのか？
Kakashi?
What's the matter with Lord Sixth?
《しかたないぞ コレ。
I have no choice…
まだ イルカ先生のは
撮影してないけど→
I don't have footage
of Iruka Sensei,
とりあえず お祝いの品として
報告しておくぞ》
but I'll report this as
my wedding gift for the time being.
(綱手)祝いの品だと～？
Wedding gift items?!
はい 忍同士の祝言がある際→
Yes, in addition to shinobi
gathering for the reception,
各人の用意した
祝いの品を査定し→
there's the standing rule
to assess the gifts everyone
will be presenting
それによって
出席者を決めるという→
in order to determine who will
be attending the wedding, correct?
取り決めがありましたよね？
あったな…。
I remember that rule…
(シズネ)カカシ様は 忍たちから
祝いの品の→
Lord Kakashi has been
in a dilemma about
報告書を
もらってからというもの→
誰をふるいにかけるべきか
ずっと悩んでおられるのです。
how he will judge and
who he will eliminate.
When you think about it,
《考えてみれば 誰だろうと→
having anyone
not being able to attend,
出席できないやつが
出てしまうと→
ヒナタも ナルトも 悲しむだろうな》
will make Naruto and Hinata
very sad.
かといって
当日の任務や警護に→
And yet, someone still has to go on
missions and be on guard that day.
誰かしら用意しなければ…。
He's worrying about that?!
そんなことで
悩んでおるのか。
ったく…。
Damn it.
《大変だぞ コレ》
This is really bad!
みんな
何か少し変な感じだったな。
Everyone's acting a little weird.
(木ノ葉丸)うわっ
ウソじゃないって コレ！
Hey! I'm not lying!
(いの)私たちの贈り物が
披露宴の参加の査定になってた!?
Our gifts will be judged
to determine
who can attend the reception?
いったい どういうこと？
それ 意味わかんないんだけど？
What's the meaning of this?
I don't get it at all!
やめてくれ
俺が悪いわけじゃないぞ コレ！
Please stop!
I'm not to blame for this!
わ！ ひどいぞコレ！
This is the worst!
(シカマル)
つまり こういうことだろ？
Well…it's like this…
ナルトとヒナタの披露宴に
木ノ葉隠れの里の忍は→
Most shinobi of the village
WEDDING RECEPTION
RECEPTION HALL
will attend
Naruto and Hinata's reception.
ほとんど参列する
だからといって→
THE VILLAGE HIDDEN
IN THE LEAVES
That said, it doesn't mean that
we won't have missions on that day.
当日の任務が
なくなるわけじゃねえ。
当直は必要だ。
THE VILLAGE HIDDEN
IN THE LEAVES
We'll need people on duty.
それに 要人たちも集まる。
Plus, we'll have important guests.
披露宴自体にも
警護がいるのは確実だ。
And it'll be crucial
to have sufficient security
for the reception.
(チョウジ)そういや ナルトとヒナタと
つきあいが多いのって→
That's right.
Many of Naruto and Hinata's friends
are top-ranked jonin.
上忍の中でも
主力ばっかだもんね。
So, what does that mean?
ってことはなんだ？ 俺たちが
式に参列するってことは→
We'll have to draw lots to see
who can attend the wedding?!
誰かが貧乏クジ
引かなきゃいけないってことか？
(リ-)そんな！ そんなのは
気持よく２人を祝えません。
No way!
If that's the case,
we won't be able to
truly celebrate with the couple!
《私たちの結婚式が
こんなことになってるなんて》
I didn't think our wedding would
cause so much trouble…
カカシ先生も
すごい悩んでるらしいぞ。
It seems this is troubling
Kakashi Sensei as well.
そうだろうな。
I see how it would.
Why did it turn into
such a big affair?
なんでこんな
大事になっちゃうんだろう。
(サイ)ナルトは
すべての里をつなげる→
Naruto's someone who connects
the entire village.
絆のような存在だからね。
大きくなるよ。
So, I guess it would
turn into a big deal.
黙って査定を待つってのか!?
そんなつもりはねえよ。
So, we just sit and wait
until the final judgement?
There's no need for that.
そういった汚れ役は
俺がやりゃいいだろ。
I'll do the dirty work,
and that'll be that.
そうです！ 皆さんが
披露宴に参加できるため→
Yes! I want everyone
to attend the reception, so…
僕も当直を志願します。
I'll volunteer for duty!
(チョウジ)そうだよね
僕も やるっきゃないよ。
That's right! I'll do it too!
(キバ)じゃあ 俺もやってやる！
ダメでしょ。
Fine, I'll sign me up too.
That's not right!
If Team 8 isn't there,
Hinata will be sad.
八班のメンバーがいなかったら
ヒナタが悲しむじゃない。
しかし 誰かが参列できずに
俺たちが優先されても→
But, I'm not okay with someone
missing the reception
納得はいかない。
just so we can.
We feel the same way.
私たちだって同じよ。
さて… 寝ていたところで
解決はできないし。
Now then,
sleeping won't solve anything.
カカシ先生。
ん？
Kakashi Sensei!
カカシ先生 すみませんでした！
I'm so sorry!
え？ あ？
Huh?
What?
ど どうした ヒナタ!? 何があった!?
W-What's wrong, Hinata?
What happened?
聞きました。
I just heard…
私たちの披露宴のせいで
カカシ先生が悩んでるって。
The dilemma you're going through,
all because our wedding reception.
え？ あ？ 何のこと？
Huh? What?
What's this about?
当日の参加者
決まってないんですよね？
You haven't decided
who can attend on that day, right?
えぇ… 聞いちゃったの？
What? You heard?
はい。
任務のことも？
Yes!
About the mission too?
はい。
何もかも？
Yes.
Everything?
はい。
そっかぁ。
Yes.
I see…
私 みんなに迷惑をかけてまで→
We would never want to
put anyone through any trouble,
祝ってもらいたいなんて
思っていません。
just to celebrate our wedding day.
え!? いや いや いや いや…。
No, no, no, no!
お前たちの披露宴を
開かないわけにはいかないから。
We have to have a reception
for you two!
だったら せめて
その日の任務や警備は→
Then is it possible, at least…
…to have the Hyuga Clan fulfill
the missions and guard duty
日向家の者に
担わせてもらえませんか。
for that day?
そんな必要ない。
えっ…。
There's no need for that!
Huh?!
祝言は お前の一族にとっても
これ以上ない晴れの席だろ。
The day of your wedding
is a happy day
for your clan too, right?
お前の家族を
一人として欠くことなく→
It's my duty as the Hokage
to make sure
every member of your family
is there for you.
参列させるのが 火影の務めだ。
そうですか…。
I…see.
当直のことは俺がなんとかする。
I'll do something about
duty assignments.
お前は何も心配いらない。
はい。
So don't worry about anything.
All right.
だから お前は
自分たちのことに集中しなさい。
Focus on yourselves, that's all.
おっと 戻らなきゃ。 じゃあな！
Oops, I'd better get back!
See you!
あ？ どうしたんだ お前ら？
What?!
What's going on, you guys?
聞きました。
We heard.
ナルトとヒナタの披露宴
誰かが出られないって。
About Naruto and Hinata's
reception…
And that some of us
won't be able to attend.
その査定をするために→
And the mission
to find the wedding gifts
お祝いを用意する任務を
出したってことも。
was in order to assess them.
そっか
お前らにまでバレちゃったか。
I see… So, you all found out too.
それで ずっと悩んでたんだって。
And also, that you've been
agonizing over this.
それも火影の仕事だしな。
It's my job as the Hokage.
それで どうした？
みんなで反対しにきたのか？
And what about it?
You're here to oppose?
いえ むしろ その逆です。
なに？
No, actually the opposite!
What?
ここにいる全員が
当直にまわるぜ。
Everyone here will handle
the assignments.
しかし そんなことしたら
肝心のナルトとヒナタが悲しむだろ。
But if you do that,
Naruto and Hinata
are sure to be sad.
だから僕たち
全員 披露宴に参加します。
That's why we're all going to
the wedding reception.
どういうことだ？
What do you mean?
つまり 当直や警備の時間を分けて
交代制にすればいい。
Simply put, we'll make a schedule
of assignments and guard duty,
and work in shifts.
負担を みんなで分け合えば→
If everyone puts in some time,
everyone can wish them well!
みんなで
あいつらを祝えるってわけだぜ。
仲間同士で助け合うってのは→
Helping each other out
is something Naruto taught us.
ナルトが教えてくれたことだしな。
どう？ カカシ先生が
しょい込む必要ないでしょ。
Well?
This way, you won't have to
bear the all the burden,
right Kakashi Sensei?
You guys…
お前ら… ありがとう。
Thank you!
でも そうなると
決まりを変えないと。
But if we do this,
we'll have to change the rule.
心配するな 石にかじりついても
必ず俺がなんとかする。
Don't worry.
Through hell or high water,
I'll think of something.
(綱手)歯が折れるぞ。
は？
You'll drown…
そもそも そんな必要はない。
Besides, there won't be a need
for all that.
綱手様。
六代目。
Lady Tsunade.
Lord Sixth…
実はな あの決まりは→
Actually that rule
was put into effect
以前 忍が結婚ラッシュになったとき→
when there was a sudden
upswing in weddings…
どうにも手が足りなくなって
発案したものだ。
…and there was
a serious shortage of manpower.
しかも あのときは大戦中だ。
In addition, that was during
the Great Ninja War.
今回と状況が違う。
The situation is different today.
それに なんといっても
今の火影はお前だ カカシ。
And more importantly,
the present Hokage is you, Kakashi.
過去の慣例にとらわれず→
Don't get caught up in old rules.
Choose the path that you believe
is most fair and just.
己が正しいと信じる道を
選べばいいんだ。
では 当直をみんなで
分担することで決定ですね。
Then you'll choose to
let us all work, right?
それはダメだ。
え？ なんでだよ！
That won't do.
Why not?!
俺の仕事は
ナルトとヒナタを祝いたい者すべてを→
My job is
to ensure that anyone who wants to
celebrate with Naruto and Hinata,
滞りなく
披露宴に参加させることだ。
is able to attend.
中座も遅刻も許さん。
I won't allow any early departures
or any late arrivals.
But there's no way around it.
(サクラ)でも
その手段がないんですよね？
俺がなんとかする。
I'll do something.
Hinata?
ヒナタ？ ヒナタじゃないか。
If it isn't Hinata!
Iruka Sensei…
イルカ先生。
なんだ？
まさか ナルトが何かやったのか？
What?!
Did Naruto do something?!
え？
うぁ～ すまん ヒナタ。
Huh?
Forgive me, Hinata!
俺 あいつに
女性との接し方なんて→
I never taught him about
how to treat women!
教えてやらなかったから。
I mean, I don't even know
about that kind of thing!
っていうか 俺が 女性との
接し方なんて知らないし。
おあっ！ んごっ ぼへっ！
何があったか知らんが→
I don't know what happened,
but please…
俺に免じて
ナルトを許してやってくれ。
For me…
Please forgive Naruto!
このとおり！
I beg of you!
フフッ アハハハッ。
なにが おかしいんだ？
What's so funny?
Iruka Sensei…
だって イルカ先生
私が何も言ってないのに→
I didn't say anything,
勝手にナルト君が悪いことした
って決めつけて→
but you decided that Naruto
must've done something bad
勝手に謝りだすから。
and started to apologize…
Oh? That's not it?
え？ 違うのか？
自分たちが結婚式をすることで→
It didn't even cross my mind
that having a wedding
たくさんの人たちに
迷惑をかけてるなんて→
would trouble so many people.
思ってもいませんでした。
But thinking back on this,
I guess I should have known.
でも 考えてみたら そうですよね。
ナルト君は今や
私たちだけじゃなく→
It's not just for us…
すべての里をつなぐ
英雄なんですもんね。
but Naruto's a hero that connects
every village together.
私 ずっと憧れてた人と
結婚できるからって→
I was probably being naïve
just thinking about marrying
the man I'd loved for so long.
舞い上がっちゃってたのかな。
You're wrong, Hinata!
それは違うぞ ヒナタ。
え？
Huh?
どんなに立派になっても
どんなに英雄になっても→
No matter how great he becomes,
no matter how big a hero
he becomes,
ナルトはナルトだ。 俺にとっても
みんなにとってもな。
Naruto will always be Naruto…
To me and to everyone.
イルカ先生。
Iruka Sensei…
Nothing will change our desire to
wish the best for you and Naruto…
お前らを祝いたい気持に
変わりはない。
だから 迷惑だなんて言うな。
So, don't think of it
as a big fuss.
はい。
Yes!
そうですか。 ヒナタには
ほんとに悪いことしちゃったな。
I see…
I feel bad for
what I put Hinata through.
イルカ先生も すみませんね。
I'm sorry too, Iruka Sensei.
Oh no, I understand how
Hinata feels too.
いやぁ でも俺も
ヒナタの気持 わかるんです。
ナルトは すべての里の人々をつなぐ
存在ですからね。
Naruto's someone that connects
everyone in every village together.
すべての里を…。
Every village…
ありがとう イルカ先生
やるべきことが見えたよ。
Thank you, Iruka Sensei!
I know what I have to do!
はい？ どういうことですか？
Huh? What do you mean?
I just have to
bow my head a little, that's all.
なに ちょっと頭を
下げてくるだけのことさ。
Iruka Sensei!
(木ノ葉丸)イルカ先生
ここにいるのはわかってるぞ。
I know you're in there!
このままじゃ 俺だけ
お祝いの品が用意できないんだぞ。
At this rate, I'll be the only one
without a wedding gift!
なんだ？
What is it?
みんなが結婚祝いを
用意してるのも→
Now that Hinata's found out about
the wedding gifts from everyone…
ヒナタにバレちゃったし サプライズも
なくなっちゃったからな→
it's no longer a surprise.
ここは 木ノ葉丸に
ひと肌 脱いでもらおうか。
So Konohamaru, I think
I'm going to put you to work!
え？ え？ なんだ？
Huh? Huh?
What is it?
WIND
And so,
というわけで 砂隠れの里の忍を→
would it be possible to dispatch
some Hidden Sand shinobi
結婚式当日に派遣して
いただけないでしょうか？
on the day of the wedding?
I kindly implore you.
なにとぞ よろしくお願いします。
Please raise your head, Lord Sixth.
頭をあげられよ 六代目。
The Raikage, Tsuchikage
and Mizukage,
雷影や土影 水影たちとも→
何ができるか考えていたんだが→
and I have all been thinking about
what we can do.
We didn't want to overdo things…
やりすぎるのも
いけないと思ってな。
俺は友人として
ナルトを祝うと言ったが→
I plan on celebrating with them
personally as Naruto's friend,
but I also wanted to do something
as the Kazekage.
それでも 風影として
できることはないか考えていた。
(カンクロウ)俺たちも 喜んで
協力させてもらうじゃん。
Now then, we'll gladly cooperate.
(我愛羅)これも すべての里に
平和と絆が生まれたおかげ。
This is all possible because of
the peaceful bond that was forged…
それは ナルトの力によるものだ。
And it was through
Naruto's strength.
我々が協力して
祝言を成功させるのは→
It's only fitting that we help
to make Naruto's wedding
当然のことだろう。
ありがとうございます。
a great success.
Thank you very much.
では お言葉に甘えて もうひとつ
お願いしてよろしいでしょうか？
Then may I be so bold
as to ask for one more favor?
なんだ？ 言ってくれ。
What is it? Please tell me.
木ノ葉丸 ちょっと。
はい！
Konohamaru! Come here!
Yes, sir!
RECORDING
Oh, a video message!
Gaara, say something!
おっ ビデオメッセージじゃん。
我愛羅 何かしゃべれ。
しゃべるって何を…。
RECORDING
Say what?
格言に決まってるだろ。
RECORDING
Like a proverb or something!
I can't come up with
something just like that!
格言など 狙って言えるか！
RECORDING
Come on! You're no Kazekage if
you can't come up with a proverb!
風影ともあろう者が→
格言のひとつも言えないなんて
ダメじゃん。
RECORDING
That's right.
うぁ～！
6 MORE DAYS
UNTIL THE WEDDING
I didn't have any parents either,
no one acknowledged me.
I did a lot of stupid stuff
to get attention.
Naruto, I think we were
very much alike.
I was your teacher back then,
and at times,
it felt like we were brothers.
But now, you're a shinobi hero.
You've really come far…
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
Hidden Leaf Story,
Th